Preliminary Guide to the Victoria Tepe Papers, 1992-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Victoria Tepe papers 1992-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Tepe, Victoria
1.2 linear feet Extent: 900 Items
Victoria Tepe, Ph.D., is an experimental psychologist and neurophysiologist, author, and advocate for women's reproductive health and rights. Collection includes materials from the abortion debate of the 1990s, including articles, essays, handbooks, and reviews. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
RL.01286
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Victoria Tepe Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Biographical Note
Victoria Tepe, Ph.D., is an experimental psychologist and neurophysiologist, author, and advocate for women's reproductive health and rights.
Collection Overview
Collection includes materials from the abortion debate of the 1990s, ranging from an Army of God handbook to the NARAL state-by-state law review. Some articles were written by Tepe, but most are third-party scholarly journals, mainstream publications, or medical reports on the physical, mental, and emotional effects of abortion.
Subject Headings
Tepe, Victoria; National Abortion and Reproductive Rights Action League; Abortion; Videocassettes
Contents of Collection
- Accession (2009-0180), 1992-2001, (2 boxes)
  Accession (2009-0180) (1.2 lin. ft.; 900 items; dated 1992-2001) includes materials from the abortion debate of the 1990s, ranging in scope from an Army of God handbook to the NARAL state-by-state abortion law review. Some articles were written by Tepe, but most are third-party scholarly journals, mainstream publications, or medical reports on the physical, mental, and emotional effects of abortion.
  [Original videotapes are closed to use. Use of these materials requires production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.]
  - Rita Townsend and Ann Perkins: Bitter Fruit: Women's Experiences of Unplanned Pregnancy, Abortion, and Adoption, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Videocassettes (Box 1)
    - Back Alley Detroit, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Dear Dr. Spencer: Abortion in a Small Town, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Caught on Camera (news clips), 2001 (Box 1)
    - Legislating a Tragedy (Box 1)
    - P.O.V.: Live Free or Die, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Abortion debate articles and publications, 1990s (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Army of God handbook, circa 1992 (Box 1)
  - Medical and scientific articles, 1990s (Box 2)
  - NARAL publications, 1990s (Box 2)
  - NARAL state-by-state law review, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Fact sheets and workbooks on pregnancy or abortion planning, 1990s (Box 2)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles, 1990s (Box 2)